Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
elementary level lesson
all about going shopping.
That's right.
Today we are going with the guy
to a shop and he's buying a new suit.
Okay, so lots of great words for men or for
buying clothes for your husband or brother.
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
We'll be back in a moment.
Hello sir, what can I do for you today?
Hello.
I need a new suit.
I have an important interview next
week so I really need to look sharp.
No problem.
We have a broad selection of suits
all tailor made so it will fit perfectly.
Great.
I want a three-piece suit, preferably
made from Italian cashmere or wool.
Very well, sir.
Would you like to have
some shirts made also?
Sure.
It will take some silver
cufflinks and a pair of silk ties.
Very good.
Now, if you will accompany me,
we can take your measurements
and choose the patterns
for your suit and shirts.
All right, we're back.
So a very simple dialogue
about a guy needing
a suit and he talked to the tailor
apparently about a couple of things now.
Why don't we take a look at some
of those words in language takeaway?
Well, first of all, a tailor is a
person who makes clothes.
So in this case, a man who makes suits.
And the first thing that we have to talk
about is the kinds of suits that he has.
He says, we have a
broad selection of suits.
Okay, so this adjective broad.
What does that mean?
It means wide.
You know, you can have a very broad street.
That means many cars can fit across it.
But in this case, we're
talking about a selection.
So that means a broad selection of suits,
very, very many suits to choose from.
Okay, so for example,
if you go to a music
store where they sell
CDs and stuff like that,
they might, they will
have a broad selection
of music so you can have rap
and hip hop and R&B, et cetera.
That's right.
Or the iTunes store has a
broad selection of music.
You can choose basically anything.
That's right.
Okay.
So a broad selection of
suits and he said, well, great.
I actually need a three piece suit.
Okay.
So there are different kinds of suits.
Some just have two pieces
like pants and the jacket.
But the kind that the man
wants is a three piece suit.
So that means there's
a jacket, pants or
trousers, some people
might say, and a vest.
Okay.
So yeah, you've
probably seen is that they
look very nice, basically under
or over your shirt, you wear a vest.
And so if you wear a vest with the
suit, it's called the three piece suit.
You know who I'm thinking of right
now, who always wears three piece suits.
He's very famous.
A football player, actually.
Beckham?
Yes.
Really?
David Beckham.
I don't know if you guys
watched the World Cup,
but in the World Cup, David Beckham
was always wearing a three piece suit.
Wow.
In that heat.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
Okay.
So we have a three piece suit.
Now we don't have a four piece suit, do we?
I don't think so.
I don't know.
Yes, you have like the, the, the,
on your watch, the Cumberbund.
Oh, Cumberbund.
That's what it's called.
Okay.
Well, that's for a tuxedo.
Now, moving on, we talk
about the materials of the suit.
And he said, well, I preferably want
something made from Italian cashmere or wool.
Okay.
So Italian is an adjective that
describes things that come from Italy.
And Italy is very famous
for its fabrics and silk.
So in this case, we're
talking about Italian
wool cashmere is a very
expensive, very soft kind of wool.
Okay.
And wool is basically
a sort of material that
comes from the, uh, from the
sheep from the hair of the sheep.
That's right.
And so different sheep,
different animals have
different kinds of wool and
these have different prices.
So some are more expensive and some
are cheaper cashmere is very expensive.
Okay.
Very good.
He also is offered some shirts and he's
like, yeah, sure, I'll take some shirts.
And I also need some silver cuff links.
Okay.
So when you close your
shirts by your, by your
wrist, you usually have a button or in some
cases, something a little bit more fancy
and when it's more
fancy, it's called a cuff link.
Yes.
You've probably seen it.
It looks like a small metal button
that you can remove from your shirt.
So it looks a lot better.
It's kind of hard to
explain, but just imagine
on your wrist, you have
a small metal button
that you can close
your shirt at the wrist.
That's right.
And some people have very, very
fancy ones with special pictures.
So you could have,
for example, a car, if you
love cars or, you know, a diamond
cuff link with a diamond on it.
That's right.
In this case, he wants a
cuff links made of silver.
And also he wants a pair of silk ties.
Okay.
So a pair of means two, he
wants two different silk ties.
And the tie is basically
a, is something that
you, you put around your neck,
men wear these usually to the office.
And ones that are made of
silk are usually more expensive.
That's right.
So a silk tie.
And okay.
So we've pretty much covered
everything that he needs.
He wants a very nice suit
with a lot of great accessories.
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be back with fluency builder.
Hello, sir.
What can I do for you today?
Hello.
I need a new suit.
I have an important interview next
week, so I really need to look sharp.
No problem.
We have a broad selection of suits,
all tailor made, so it will fit perfectly.
Great.
I want a three-piece suit, preferably
made from Italian cashmere or wool.
Very well, sir.
Would you like to have
some shirts made also?
Sure.
I also take some silver
cufflinks and a pair of silk ties.
Very good.
Now, if you will
accompany me, we can take
your measurements and choose
the patterns for your suit and shirts.
So in fluency builder,
today we have three very
useful phrases that
you can say when you're
with the tailor at the at
the store buying a suit.
The first one is to look sharp.
That's right.
He says that he has a job
interview and he wants to look sharp.
Okay.
So to look means to have the appearance
of but sharp, what does this mean?
Basically, take it as a
chunk or as a phrase
and if you look sharp,
it means you look
smart, you look good, you
look clean, you look very nice.
So this is normally
something we say to men.
You look really sharp today
or I want him to look sharp.
I'm going to buy him a nice silk tie.
That's right.
So to look sharp, as I said, to look very
nice, very clean, very handsome, okay.
So looking sharp.
And well, when we
were talking about the
suit, the person mentioned
that all the suits are tailor-made.
Alright, this is a very
important phrase if you
want to go shopping for
clothes that are made for you.
So something is tailor-made if the
sizes are made only for fitting you.
That's right.
If you go to the
department store and you
buy a suit off of the shelf or
the rack, it's not tailor-made.
But if the tailor
makes it, he sews it to
your size, then it's
tailor-made and you know,
wedding dresses are tailor-made,
special suits are tailor-made.
So this is usually an
expensive kind of clothing.
Okay, so it basically means the tailor,
the person made it, especially for you.
That's right.
And the opposite, as you said,
would be off the rack, off the rack.
And this means that
when you go to the store,
you pick something,
you like it, and you buy it.
There's no one going, no one is
going to sew it to make it fit you.
That's right.
So this is actually how
most of us get our clothes.
You go to the
department store, you get a
pair of jeans, a t-shirt, obviously
all that stuff is off the rack.
It's not tailor-made for your size.
That's right.
Okay.
But if you really
want to get something
tailor-made, you need to be
able to talk to the tailor about it.
And so he will usually say, "Let
me take your measurements.
" Mm-hmm.
This is our next phrase.
That's right.
The tailor mentioned that he wants to take
him over there and take his measurements.
So when the tailor
says, "I want to take your
measurements or I need to take your
measurements," what does that mean?
That means I need to measure parts
of your body to help make the suit.
So he will normally
measure your shoulders, your
waist, your hips, and
how long things will be.
So your arms and your legs.
And these are all important measurements to
know how big or how small to make the suit.
That's right.
You want the tailor to
take your measurements
or you can also say, "You
have to get measured.
" That's right.
So to get measured
or to take someone's
measurement, these are key
phrases for buying a tailor-made suit.
Very good.
Okay.
I'll have one last time and
we'll be back to talk some more.
Hello, sir.
What can I do for you today?
Hello.
I need a new suit.
I have an important interview next
week, so I really need to look sharp.
No problem.
We have a broad selection of suits,
all tailor-made, so it will fit perfectly.
Great.
We have three-piece suit, preferably
made from Italian cashmere or wool.
Very well, sir.
Would you like to have
some shirts made, also?
Sure.
I also take some silver
cufflinks and a pair of silk ties.
Very good.
Care measurements and choose
the patterns for your suit and shirts.
So do you have any
tailor-made suits, Marco?
I actually don't.
I haven't -- oh, here to the
office, I never wear a suit.
You don't really need
to wear suits, all fancy.
And there have been
very few occasions where
I've needed a suit, so I actually
don't have a suit at the moment.
Not even one.
I left them all at home
and I just haven't used them.
And probably they wouldn't fit anymore.
This is the problem with
getting things tailor-made as well.
The thing is that with a tailor-made suit,
usually it's made to get bigger or smaller.
So maybe the shoulders and the arms are the
same, but if you gain weight or you lose
weight, the tailor can make
those small, small changes.
That's right.
Actually I had a friend who
got some tailor-made jeans.
And I think that
would be nice, because
sometimes I don't know,
jeans for me, they don't
fit well.
Yeah, I mean either.
There's a very famous
company that does
tailor-made jeans that I
was thinking about going
to, because I hate
buying jeans off the rack.
Yeah, they usually don't fit either.
The waist is too -- I
need a bigger waist,
but then everything
is too baggy and it just
doesn't look right or
everything is too small.
So I think this is a
very interesting thing,
although I don't know
how expensive it would
be, because getting tailor-made
clothes is relatively expensive.
It can be very expensive, although
that's usually in America or in Europe.
In places like India
and China, I think it's
much more common to have things
made to fit you, the other made.
This is a very interesting subject, and
actually we are wondering if maybe you know
a tailor, you are a tailor or you've
gotten things tailor-made for you.
You got married
recently and you had a
tailor-made tuxedo or a
tailor-made wedding dress.
That's right, so let us know.
We can be found at EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
Bye, guys.
Bye.